Aside from improved typescript support
除了改善了typescript支持
the two reasons we want to use the composition API are
还有我们使用composition API的其他两个原因
to organize things by feature
按特性组织内容
and to make the code reusable across other components
并使代码在其他组件之间可重用
and right now are sample code doesn't neither
而现在我们的示例代码都没有
so let's refactor
所以我们来重构一下
as if we wanted to make things more modular
我们想要代码更模块化一些
Here is our current code
这是我们目前的代码
this is nothing new based on what we've built
这是我们在之前的代码上写好的
However I am now using refs
现在使用的是refs
because honestly I think it's a little simpler
因为说实话，我觉得refs的使用更简单一点
To organized the code by feature
为了按功能组织代码
I would move the code out of the setup method
我会把代码移出setup方法
create a new function called useEventSpace
创建一个叫做useEventSpace的函数
which is our composition function
这是我们的复合函数
And then call this composition function our setup method
然后从我们的setup方法中调用这个复合函数
Now our component is organized by feature
我们的组件是按功能组织的
And if there was additional features I wanted to add
如果我想添加其他功能
I could just start reading another composition function
我可以写另外一个复合函数
what if I wanted to make this code were reusable across other components
如果我想让跨组件使用代码呢
To do this, I would move my composition function into another file
为了实现这个,我就把复合函数移到另一个文件中
Let's put it in the use directory and call it events-sapce.js
把它放入use目录中，event-space.js
I'll then export this function
然后导出
and then import into our component
然后引入到我们的组件中
that's all there is to it
就在这儿这样写
What if I wanted to add another composition function
如果我想添加另一个复合函数呢?
inside this component called event mapping
在这个组件里面叫做事件的映射
to map out the location of the event
用来映射标出活动地点
Well, I would just import it
好吧,我会直接引入
and then inside the setup function you might think that I would just
然后在setup函数中,你也许会认为我会
call both function
调用这两个函数
But actually, this isn't valid JavaScript
但实际上这不是有效的js脚本
we can't create objects like this
我们不能创建这样的对象
instead I would restructure the object that each of these return
相反，我会重构这些对象在return中返回
giving my template access to everything it needs to render
给我的模板访问它需要呈现的一切
Our solution is pretty efficient
解决方案相当有效
But my coding this way we've introduced a problem
但是通过这种方式编码导致了一个新问题
it's not clear by looking at this file
这些复合函数写的并不是很清晰的注入到哪个文件中
which objects are being injected by which composition function
this was one of the problems we previously had with Mixin
这个问题和以前Mixin的问题是同样的
to solve this, we can create local objects
为了解决这个问题,我们可以在当前页面创建一些对象
for the data that are composition functions are sending in
所有这些我们可以为合成函数发送的数据创建本地对象
and then use those in the return object
然后在return对象中使用它们
now it's explicit which objects are coming from which composition function
现在它明确了哪些对象来自哪个组合函数
this is a Vue3.0 best practice
这是Vue3.0 最好的例子